EMANUEL DE AGUIAR

+1 (254) 648-6581 · emanueldeaguiar99@gmail.com · Planaltina, Brazil www.linkedin.com/in/emanuel-de-aguiar-19aa54327 · https://emanuel-portfolio-zeta.vercel.app

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I've been working as a software engineer for more than 12 years. Started my carrier with HTML, CSS, PHP and Laravel, and 2 years later, I mainly worked with JS/TS, Python and modern JS frameworks like React, Angular, Vue.js on the frontend and Node, Django on the backend. Mainly worked with Nosql database, Have a lot of experience with AWS like Lambda, EC2, DynamoBD. Writing clean, scalable, reusable code, excellent communication skills, strong problem solving skills are my greatest strengths.

STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

- Frontend: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Angular.js, Vue.js, MUI, Tailwind CSS, BootStrap, Three.js, WebGL, React Native
- Backend: Python, Django, PHP, Laravel, Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, RabbitMQ, Redis, Docker, Kubernetes, Java
- Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, FireStore
- Test: Jest, React testing library, Cypress, Mocha
- Could Platforms: AWS, GCP, Microsoft Azure
- DevOps Tools: Jenkins, Github Actions, Terraform

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Dandy

Senior Software Engineer

February 2023 - October 2024

- Worked as a senior full stack developer with TS, React and React Native on the frontend, Nest.js on the backend.
- Built reusable, maintainable and modular UI components in React for web app and React Native for mobile apps.
- Ensured that the mobile apps developed with React Native function smoothly across both IOS and Android platforms.
- Optimized the performance of the app by minimizing load times, reduced bundle sizes.
- Integrated frontend components with backend services using GraphQL.
- Deployed to AWS, used Lambda for serverless architecture, Redis for caching.
- Worked within a Scrum, Agile methodologies

Keeper Memorials

August 2019 - December 2022

Full Stack Engineer

- Worked as a full stack developer, JS/TS and Next.js on the frontend, Python, Django on the backend.
- Developed UI using Next.js and TS, ensuring a seamless UX, applications are fully responsive and work across all devices.
- Optimize frontend code to improve load times and performance.
- Designed and developed GraphQL APIs to enable communication between the frontend and backend.
- Worked with PostgreSQL and Firebase to design schemas, write queries and managed data.
- Implemented secure authentication and authorization systems.

Full Stack Developer

- Worked as a frontend developer, JS/TS and React/Nextjs on the frontend.
- Developed UI using Nextjs and TS, ensuring a seamless UX, applications are fully responsive and work across all devices.
- Optimize frontend code to improve load times and performance.
- Designed and developed GraphQL APIs to enable communication between the frontend and backend.
- Worked within a Scrum, Agile methodology, focusing on iterative development, collaboration with cross-functional teams, and continuous improvement to ensure timely delivery of features and high-quality software

BloomBoard

February 2015 - December 2016

Frontend Developer

- Designed and Built reusable React components to create a dynamic and interactive user interface.
- Implemented responsive designs to ensure a seamless experience across various devices and screen sizes.
- Used state management libraries such as Redux and Context API to manage application state effectively.
- Optimized React application performance by implementing techniques like lazy loading, code splitting and memorization.
- Wrote unit and integration tests for React components using testing libraries such as Jest and React testing library.

<u>Azul</u>

September 2012 - December 2014

Junior Software Developer

- Collaborated with a team of developers to create and maintain the frontend of a digital freight marketplace.
- Participated in code reviews and collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high quality software solutions.
- Engaged in troubleshooting and debugging efforts to resolve frontend issues and optimize user experience.
- Conducted research on emerging technologies and industry trends to inform development decisions and improve project outcomes.
- Actively participated in team meetings and discussions to brainstorm ideas and problem-solve challenges encountered during development.

Freelancer Site

February 2011 - July 2012

Freelance Developer

- Worked on Freelancer site as a junior software engineer with C++ and PHP.
- Built efficient and scalable applications.
- Learned new technologies, programming languages and frameworks like PHP and Laravel, WordPress.
- · Experienced hands-on coding while building the small features and components

EDUCATION

Yokohama National University
Bachelor of Computer Science

October 2006 - October 2010